Contact

Queens, New York 6462403815 (Home) mc7073@nyu.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/rachel-chia24365171 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Microsoft Excel Microsoft Office Nursing

Certifications

Infection Control and Barrier Precautions

COVID-19 Pulmonary, ARDS and Ventilator Resources

Mental Health First Aid

COVID-19 Contact Tracing

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Rachel Chi

Incoming Registered Nurse at Northwell Health & COVID test RN at CORE

New York

Summary

Motivated, talented, and compassionate, multilingual (Mandarin, Cantonese & Fujianese) new graduate Registered Nurse with emerging experience in the delivery of evidence-based, patient-centered care in diverse clinical settings and medical specialties. Outcomes focused healthcare professional with one year of MA experience and a proven ability to quickly cultivate strong relationships with patients and healthcare providers to deliver holistic care promoting a timely return to peak levels of health and wellness. Determined, self-starter recognized among preceptors for strengths in in critical thinking, clinical judgement, and professionalism in managing routine and emergency medical situations. Eager to utilize professional training, credentials, and experiences to contribute to the health and wellness of patients by serving in a challenging, rewarding new graduate RN role within a Medical-Surgical care setting.

Experience

Northwell Health
Registered Nurse
August 2020 - Present (1 month)
FOREST HILL. QUEENS, New York

Community Organized Relief Effort Registered Nurse June 2020 - August 2020 (3 months) Astoria, Queens, New York

Provided instructions, resources, and support to individuals preparing to undergo COVID-19 testing procedures to minimize anxieties and increase treatment compliance; Created, maintained, and provide practice environments that help meet the medical needs of the community within a system that protects nurses, medical assistants, and other employees. This included the provision of PPE, the implementation of infection control,

the training of operational protocols, the supervision of COVID-testing performance; Provided clinical leadership, implemented and evaluated patient care processes and testing delivery; Collaborated with other health professional team members and provided team leadership.

NYU Langone Hospital—Brooklyn

Volunteer

August 2019 - June 2020 (11 months)

Supported patient care team by coordinating with lab for timely specimen delivery, feeding patients according to diet orders, answering call-bells, offering companionship, transporting, and closely monitoring patients one- to-one.

VNS Knickerbocker Village & Smith House Nursing Student September 2019 - December 2019 (4 months) New York, New York, United States

Visting Nurse

Downtown Gastrointestinal Association Medical Assistant July 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 4 months) New York, United States

- o Prepare patient for Endoscopy and Colonoscopy by providing informed consent, patient education, completing pre-procedure check lists and collecting baseline vital signs
- o Sent biopsy and explain report of Endoscopy and Colonoscopy for patient

NYU Kimmel Center
Nursing Student
June 2019 - August 2019 (3 months)
New York, New York, United States

GI Med-Surg units & Pediatrics Nursing

NYU Tisch Hospital Nursing Student March 2019 - June 2019 (4 months) New York, New York, United States

Psychiatric Nursing

NYU Langone Hospital—Brooklyn Nursing Student September 2018 - March 2019 (7 months) Brooklyn, New York, United States

Neurocritical & Pulmonary Med-Surg units

Pain Management
Medical Assistant
September 2017 - July 2018 (11 months)
New York, United States

Accompanied physicians during patient appointments to collect detailed medical history, vital signs, and assessments results to support physicians in effectively diagnosing and managing a broad range of chronic pain-related conditions.; Readied patients to undergo invasive and noninvasive procedures by obtaining informed consent and completing preprocedural checklists to ensure ability of individuals to undergo medical care with minimal risks of adverse results.; Collaborated with physicians and nurses to impart discharge education, instructions, and referrals to maximize the potential for optimal results; Played a pivotal role in monitoring post-op care by maintaining open communication with patients regarding treatment regimen efficacy and compliance.

Education

New York University
ABS, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2018 - 2019)

Hunter College
Bachelor's degree, Nutrition Sciences · (2015 - 2017)